You 're not getting a bike , love , not at the moment .
- BOY : But , Mum ... - But nothing .
- Please ? - I said not at the moment .
Maybe next year , OK ?
Sweetie , I said maybe next year .
Stuart Macken says our Jeep looks like something
a " fedophile " would drive .
- And who 's Stuart Macken ? - In my class .
- Is he your friend ? - He 's an ass-face .
Hey .
Can I say " anus face " ?
- No . - But it 's a science word .
- Mum , look out ! - ( TIRES SCREECH )
SARAH : Are you all right ?
- Chris , are you all right ? - Yes .
Don 't move .
Are you OK ?
I didn 't see you , you came out of nowhere .
( WHISPERING ) He 's not my son , he 's not my son ...
he 's not my son , he 's not my son ,
he 's not my son , he 's not my son ...
( CONTINUES TO WHISPER )
( CHRIS GRUNTING )
" I 'm Chuck , the strongest soldier in the whole land ,
and you 're nothing but a little weakling . "
( HIGH VOICE ) " No , please , leave me alone ! "
( CHRIS GRUNTING , PLAY-ACTING ) " Silence , weakling ! "
You finished ?
- Chris ? - It 's gone cold .
Put some more cheese on it .
I don 't like that dust cheese .
Then don 't put more cheese on it . Just finish it , please .
Three ...
CHRIS : Two ...
One !
( CHRIS LAUGHS )
- Mum wins . You know the rules . - Aw .
( CUTLERY RATTLING ON PLATE )
( LIGHT BUZZING )
CHRIS : Mum !
What is it , sweetie ?
( CLATTER )
Quick !
Chris ?
There 's another one .
SARAH : You 're getting far too big to be scared of them .
What if it comes back inside ?
She won 't .
How do you know it 's a girl ?
Eight legs and no willy , see ?
- Why don 't you just kill it ? - What did she ever do to you ?
- Encrotched on my personal space . - ( CHUCKLES )
It 's " encroached , " and I don 't think she did it on purpose .
Dad would kill it for me .
I 'm not Dad .
Why did we move here without him ?
It 's not that simple , sweetie .
Why ?
- It 's just not , OK ? - Why ?
You said he 'd be right behind us . You 're a liar .
- Liar ! - Chris !
- Liar ! - Sweetie ...
( SIGHS )
Chris ! Wait !
Christopher !
( PANTING )
Chris ?
Christopher !
( TREE CREAKING )
( DISTANT CRACKLE )
( DISTANT ANIMAL SHRIEKS )
Chris ?
( WIND BLOWING )
- Mum ? - ( GASPS )
Never run off on me like that again , OK ?
I 'm sorry .
Me too .
I know that Dad makes you sad .
Love you .
I love you , too .
Mum ?
What is that ?
Nothing .
Come on , let 's go home .
MAN ON TV : Anne ? This is Woody .
Well , I have a ticket for the Hi-Teen Carnival Saturday ,
and ... well , would you like to go ?
ANNE : Why , yes , Woody .
I 'll have to talk to my folks about it but I think I can go .
- That 'll be fun ! - ( SARAH SIGHS )
WOODY : Yeah .
Well , shall I pick you up about eight o 'clock ?
ANNE : That 's fine , Woody .
( CREAK )
( LOCK CLICKS )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( CHILDREN SHOUTING , CHATTER )
Are you gonna show me that ?
You should sign up .
Might be a good way of making new friends .
Don 't wanna make new friends .
You know , when I was your age , I moved town once , too .
I was really scared about going to this new place where I 'd never been .
But when I got there , my mum signed me up for the Brownies ,
and before I knew it , I had a whole group of new friends .
So , maybe that might happen to you if you sign up for this .
Maybe .
You 'll settle in , sweetie .
We 're gonna be happy living here .
I promise .
JAY : Well , he had one of those faces ...
you just wanted to punch over and over and over again .
- You know , like this ? - ( LOUISE AND ROB CHUCKLE )
ROB : You 've never punched anyone in your entire life .
JAY : I punched Tom Drum .
ROB : That poor kid who always had the moustache of snot under his nose ?
JAY : That 's the one , yeah .
Yeah , I punched him square in the forehead , remember ?
Why ?
It was years ago . It doesn 't matter .
But the thing is , he gets out of his car .
And he 's walking towards me , screaming at me that I cut him off ,
- and he 's raging ... - You want a bloody degree to open this .
That 's you fucked , isn 't it ?
( SCOFFS ) And when are you planning on graduating ?
Jay 's a permanent student .
- JAY : I 'm a lecturer . - Assistant lecturer .
I am shaping impressionable minds .
LOUISE : Sarah studied teaching too .
Well , I only did a year . I , uh ... had to drop out .
I got pregnant with Chris and kind of took a different path .
I 'm glad your path took you down here . Best employee I ever had .
JAY : How is that junk shop of yours anyway ?
Rob , tell your brother he 's an asshole .
You 're an asshole .
LOUISE : So , what happened with the guy who hit your car ?
Oh , yeah , yeah . So , anyway , he comes over to the car , right ?
And he puts his hand on the bonnet .
And I swear he 's not gonna budge an inch ,
and he 's glaring right at me , and you can see ...
- ROB : Sounds like Walkie-Talkie . - JAY : Who 's that ?
Walkie-Talkie .
It 's this crazy old lady who lives up in the hills near here .
Near the bridge by your house . You must have seen her .
JAY : Yeah , that 's the woman you told me murdered her kid .
She didn 't murder him .
- No ? - No .
Tell the story .
There 's no story .
No . Go on .
LOUISE : Her son James was in my class , used to sit across from me in school .
He was really nice , friendly , really into nature , I remember .
He used to have , um , ants in a pencil case under his desk .
Anyway , when we were around eight , Noreen ...
Noreen Brady 's her name ...
she came bursting into the classroom .
Out of control , screaming insane things about him .
It took three teachers to drag her into the principal 's office
and lock her in before the police came .
Nobody knew what was wrong with her .
He was taken out of school for a while , and ...
she went away to have her head fixed .
- And then , a few months later ... - She got out ...
got a car and mowed the kid down .
LOUISE : No . No , that 's not what happened .
It was an accident . It was an awful tragedy .
The poor woman .
( CREAK , BANG )
( WIND BLOWING )
( CREAK )
( BANG )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( CLATTER )
Chris ?
( BANG , CREAK )
Sweetie ?
What are you doing down here ?
( CREAK , BANG )
( WIND BLOWING )
( CREAKING )
( DOOR SLAMS , CREAKING )
( DOOR SLAMS )
( CREAKING )
( GASPS )
( SARAH BREATHING HEAVILY )
( TWIGS RUSTLING )
( TWIG SNAPS )
( GASPS )
Christopher ?
( PHONE RINGING )
- MALE OPERATOR : Emergency . - Um , is this the police ?
No , but I can connect you to the police . What 's the emergency ?
It 's my son , he 's missing .
- OK , what 's your address , please ? - Uh ... there 's , um ...
There 's no number on the house .
- Tell me what town you 're in . - No , someone might 've taken him .
You 're gonna have to stay calm and tell me where you live
if you want me to help you .
- OK ? - ( DOOR CREAKS )
Hello ?
- Hello ? - CHRIS : Mummy ?
- Hel ... - ( PHONE HANGS UP )
Where were you ?
Chris ! Where were you ?
- Here . - No , you weren 't .
Are you OK , Mummy ?
- How long you been in the area ? - Um , just a few weeks .
And has it only been since the move that you 've felt like this ?
Any history of anxiety disorders in your family ?
- No . - Have you ever been on medication ?
- No . - How about that scar ?
May I see it , please ?
That 's quite the bump .
- Yeah , I was in an accident . - Not so long ago , by the look of it .
About a year ago . It just sometimes gets irritated .
This is three weeks ' worth .
It 's not too heavy but best to take before bed .
Check back in with me then , and we 'll see how you 're doing , OK ?
( CARTOON PLAYING ON TV )
MAN ON TV : Ah , my prairie flower !
- Fly with me ! - ( WOMAN SHRIEKS )
What do you say , toots ?
SARAH : Sweetie , dinner 's ready !
- You shall have diamonds ! - ( BETTY BOOP GASPS )
Like those sparkling eyes of yours .
- Ooh ! - Blue white diamonds !
- Chris ! - Mummy ?
( GASPS )
- I thought you were upstairs . - You called me .
Must be pretty hungry .
I 'm starving .
Good morning , Mummy .
- Where did you get those ? - The garden .
You know you 're not supposed to go outside on your own .
I wanted to surprise you .
Let me see .
They 're beautiful . Thank you .
I can hear your heart beat .
How does it sound ?
Peaceful .
( CHILDREN SHOUTING , CHATTER )
So , what are your new friends ' names ?
Michael and Peter and Sam and Stuart .
Stuart ? Stuart Macken ?
I thought you didn 't like him .
- I don 't have to be his friend . - No , no .
Making new friends is good , remember ?
It 's OK , sweetie .
( HONKS HORN )
Stay here , OK ?
Excuse me ?
Can you move off the road , please ?
( WOMAN WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY )
Mrs. Brady ?
It 's not your boy .
MAN : Noreen ?
I 'm sorry . She ...
She likes to wander .
I told her to keep to the side , but , uh ...
she 's not a great listener .
Des .
Sarah .
And what 's the little man 's name , eh ?
I should get going .
If you ever need anything ...
Thanks .
- He 's not your son ! - DES : Noreen !
- He 's not your son ! - ( BANGING )
Not your son .
Noreen !
( RADIO PLAYING )
( VARIOUS POP SONGS AND DIALOGUE )
RADIO : Looking beyond this morning , coastal counties and further inland ,
it will be on the cool side for this time of year .
It 's definitely a week of contrasts ahead , with many scattered showers ...
I 'm just gonna stop for one minute .
Don 't move a muscle , OK ?
( BIRDS CAWING )
Noreen ?
MAN : " I then approached the woman .
She was crouched down on the ground in front of her house .
I thought she was looking for something ,
maybe something she had lost .
But when I got closer , I saw that her head was buried in the ground .
And I tried to dig it out ... "
( VOICE FADES INTO BACKGROUND )
Ms. O 'Neill ? Are you happy to sign this ?
- Ms. O 'Neill ? - ( CHRIS LAUGHS )
- Ms. O 'Neill ? - CHRIS : I 'm strong ...
Do you want to change anything ?
MAN : Double or nothing . Go on . See ? Look at that . It 's too easy .
( SINKHOLE GURGLES )
Morning .
Hey . I thought I told you to take a few days .
I know , I 'm just not good at sitting around the house .
Oh , I hear ya .
Why do you think I opened this place ?
- So , how was your weekend ? - Fine .
Must 've been quite a shock .
Finding her like that .
Is it true ? The way she was ?
Sorry , I don 't mean to probe . Sorry .
- It 's just it 's so bizarre . - I know .
And how 's Chris ?
Yeah . He 's fine , thanks .
Do you ever look at your kids and not recognize them ?
Yeah , twins are usually hidden under a layer of shite .
Or food , or both . And as for Saoirse ...
Jesus ! It 's all about the eyebrows these days .
Not how they look , but how they are .
- Their personalities . - Of course .
They swing from monsters to angels and back again in the blink of an eye .
You all right ?
Yeah .
Just a funny few days .
( CREAK )
- DES : Sarah ? - ( GASPS )
Sorry for your loss .
I 'm just glad she 's at peace now .
They wanted me to put a lid on ,
but she 'll be in the dark long enough .
Will you join me ?
- ( DRINK POURING ) - OK .
Thanks .
DES : James . He , uh ...
lost that tooth playing hurling . ( CHUCKLES )
He thought it a badge of honor .
He 's cute .
He was .
I remember the day he was born .
Noreen said she finally understood what life was all about .
We both did .
You , did you get that same feeling when your little man was born ?
And what 's his name ? I didn 't catch it the last time we met .
Christopher .
Chris .
She didn 't mean him any harm , you know ?
Why did she say he wasn 't my son ?
That 's what Noreen did .
Just after his eighth birthday , Noreen started to say that ...
James was ... different .
She saw tiny , insignificant things only a mother would notice .
It was like little pebbles rolling down a hill , you know ?
Then you blink and it becomes a landslide .
A specialist had some fancy name for whatever fuse had popped ,
but putting a label on it didn 't make her any better .
She was convinced .
Of what ?
That he was an impostor .
Wasn 't her son .
I suppose when she saw your Chris ,
it reminded her of our James .
What happened to him ?
He was hit by a car .
My car .
I didn 't see him dart out on the road .
Well ...
here I am , eh ?
Maudlin as that bunch of ...
professional mourners lurking out there .
I always think it 's better to ... remember happier times .
Thanks for coming by .
( TREE CREAKS )
( GROUND RUMBLING GENTLY )
( WHISPERING SOUNDS )
Do you remember those beautiful flowers you picked for me in the garden ?
CHRIS : Yes .
Have you been going anywhere else ?
No .
Like the forest , maybe ?
No , Mummy .
So , how 's Chuck doing ?
Haven 't seen you play with him lately .
He 's still your favorite , right ?
Are you sure you haven 't been going into the forest on your own ?
No , Mummy .
Then how did he get out there ?
- No more lies , Christopher . - I 'm not .
- Tell me the truth . - I am .
- Tell me the truth ! - I am !
- Stop lying to me ! - I 'm not lying !
I 'm sorry , Mummy .
( WATER DRIPPING )
( CHRIS GIGGLES )
( PITTER-PATTER )
( PITTER-PATTER CONTINUES )
( BREATHY VOICE )
( PITTER-PATTER )
( SHARP HISS )
( EXCITED BREATHING )
( GASPS )
( SARAH BREATHING HEAVILY )
( FLOORBOARD CREAKS )
CHRIS : Mummy ? Is that you ?
( CREAKING )
( SING-SONG ) Mummy ?
( SING-SONG ) Chris .
Where are you ?
In bed , why ?
( APPROACHING FOOTSTEPS )
Good night , Mummy .
Good night , sweetie .
- ( DEPARTING FOOTSTEPS ) - ( SIGH OF RELIEF )
- And in . - ( CHRIS INHALES )
- And out . - ( CHRIS EXHALES )
- And in . - ( INHALES )
- And out . - ( EXHALES )
- And a big , deep one . - ( INHALES )
DOCTOR : It 's not the most unusual thing I 've heard of a kid eating .
Yeah , but usually he 's petrified of them .
There 's something not right with him lately .
I can 't put my finger on it , but I know .
I just know he 's not himself .
And how are you feeling ?
Is the medication helping ?
May I ask you a personal question ?
Yeah .
Chris 's father , is he around ?
And that scar on your head ...
was it actually an accident , Sarah ?
( BLEEP )
- ( TV PLAYING ) - ( GIGGLING )
( INDISTINCT DIALOGUE ON TV )
( CONTINUES TO GIGGLE )
MAN : .. picked him up to have a chat . Hired me , right there on the spot .
- Three tours ... - ( GIGGLES )
So , which one of you boys can sing ?
( BLEEP )
( CREAK )
What are you doing , Mummy ?
Washing .
Morning .
I finished it .
Are you hungry ?
Come on .
You know I love you very much , sweetie .
I 'm sorry if I 've been acting a little strange lately . It 's just that ...
sometimes when you 're a grown-up , life gets all blocked up with worry .
But then I look at you and ...
I remember what life is really all about .
Chris ...
( SARAH GRUNTS IN PAIN )
( CHRIS SINGING SCALES )
( CONTINUES TO SING SCALES )
( APPLAUSE )
TEACHER : Next up , we have my class .
So , please , put your hands together for the Rattlin ' Boggers !
- ( APPLAUSE ) - ( PIANO PLAYING LIVELY SONG )
ALL : â  ª O-ro the rattlin ' bog The bog down in the valley-o
â  ª O-ro the rattlin ' bog The bog down in the valley-o
â  ª Now in that bog there was a hole
â  ª A rare hole , a rattlin ' hole
â  ª A hole in the bog In the bog down in the valley-o
ALL : â  ª O-ro the rattlin ' bog The bog down in the valley-o
â  ª O-ro the rattlin ' bog The bog down in the valley-o
GIRL : â  ª Now in that hole there was a tree
â  ª A rare tree , a rattlin ' tree
â  ª A tree in the hole In the hole in the bog
â  ª In the bog down in the valley-o
ALL : â  ª O-ro the rattlin ' bog The bog down in the valley-o
â  ª O-ro the rattlin ' bog The bog down in the valley-o
â  ª Now on that branch there was a limb
â  ª A rare limb , a rattlin ' limb
â  ª With the limb on the branch ...
On the branch on the tree ...
on the tree ...
in the hole ...
in the hole in the bog ...
in the bog ...
down in ...
the valley-o .
( HEAVY BREATHING )
WOMAN : Sarah ?
Sarah ?
Are you all right ?
He 's not my son .
Chris ?
- Whose son is he ? - I don 't know , but it 's not Chris .
I don 't know what you mean .
I know I sound crazy , but if it was yours , you would know .
OK . Let 's go for a walk .
Sarah ... let 's get some air .
Did you see me ?
Mummy ?
- What 's wrong ? - Wasn 't he brilliant ?
Sarah ?
- ( VOICES BECOME DISTANT ) - You OK , Ms. O 'Neill ?
Mummy ?
Mummy !
( BLEEP )
( DRINK POURING )
( DES CHUCKLES )
I 've seen myself grow old from too many angles .
Even after 30 years , she still checked me every day .
Checked you for what ?
That I was still me .
The mirror always tells the truth .
That 's what she 'd say .
( BLEEP )
I need to show you something .
What was wrong with James , I think it 's happening to Chris .
- There was nothing wrong with James . - Please , just look at it .
CHRIS ON VIDEO : What are you doing , Mummy ?
Please .
SARAH ON VIDEO : Washing .
Why don 't you stay up here and play with your toys ?
Do you see it ?
That can 't be my son .
Tell me you see him . Tell me .
I 'm sorry . I can 't see anything .
- Noreen was right . - Enough .
- He wasn 't your son ! - Enough .
Chris isn 't Chris , and James wasn 't James !
- Enough ! - ( CAMERA CLATTERS )
Then tell me I 'm wrong .
Tell me I 'm crazy . Tell me .
I can 't .
Mummy ?
Why did you run away from me at school ?
I wasn 't feeling too good .
Do you feel better now ?
Yeah . Much .
You won 't run away on me again , will you ?
No .
I don 't like being left on my own .
You hungry ?
I 'll make your favorite .
I love you , Mummy .
I love you , too .
Dinner 's ready !
Come on , before it gets cold .
Don 't you want some ?
You know I don 't like the dust cheese , remember ?
( EXPLOSIONS , GUNFIRE ON TV )
- BOY : Chuck ? - MAN : That 's damn right , soldier .
You need to be more careful with your weapon , trooper ...
You know what we haven 't played in a while ?
Our game .
Our favorite .
Three ...
two ...
one .
You 're not my son .
You 're not Chris .
What 's wrong with you , Mummy ?
You 're not my son .
( LOW GROWL )
( SARAH GASPS )
- ( SARAH SCREAMS ) - ( CLATTER )
- SARAH : Get your hands off me ! - ( CHRIS SNARLS )
- ( BLOWS LANDING ) - ( SARAH YELPS )
Don 't , please !
( SCREAMS )
( SARAH SPLUTTERING )
- ( WIND BLOWING ) - ( HEAVY BREATHING )
( COUGHING , SPLUTTERING )
( GASPING )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( LIGHT BUZZING )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( CHRIS BREATHING PEACEFULLY )
( CHRIS SNARLS AND HISSES )
( GROWLS )
What have you done with him ?
( SNARLS )
- ( THUD ) - ( SARAH CHOKING )
( THUD )
( SARAH PANTING )
( DEMONIC SHRIEKING )
( SHRIEKING CONTINUES )
( SHRIEKING QUIETENS )
( DISTANT MOAN )
( COUGHING )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( GRUNTING )
( PANTING )
( GRUNTS )
( ROCK RATTLES )
( GASPS )
( SOIL FALLS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GASPS )
( PANICKED BREATHING )
( WHISPERS ) It 's me . It 's Momma Bear .
( RUSTLING )
( GROWLING )
( SNARLING )
( MOANING )
( WHISPERING SOUNDS )
( DEMONIC ROARING )
( GURGLING )
( SNARLING )
- ( SNARLS ) - ( SARAH YELPS )
( PANICKED GRUNTS )
( THUD )
- ( HURRIED FOOTSTEPS ) - ( SARAH PANTING )
Chris , wake up .
Chris ?
Wake up . Wake up .
Come on .
Chris , wake up .
- ( CHRIS MOANS ) - Yeah , yeah .
Yeah , yeah . Yeah .
OK , OK .
You stay here , OK ?
( DOOR CREAKS )
( DISTANT CLATTER )
( CHRIS WHEEZING )
( WEAKLY ) Mummy .
Mummy .
- ( DOOR RATTLES ) - Mummy .
( DOOR RATTLES )
( FIRE CRACKLING )
( FLAMES WHOOSH , CRACKLE )
( SNIFFLES )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
( CAMERA CLICKING )
â  ª There was an old woman Who lived in the woods
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª She had a baby three months old
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª She had a pen-knife long and sharp
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª She stuck that knife In the baby 's heart
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª There were three loud knocks Come a-knockin ' on the door
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Three loud knocks Come a-knockin ' at the door
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª There were two policemen and a man
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Two policemen and a man
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª They took her away And they put her in the jail
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª They put a rope around her neck
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª They pulled the rope and she got hung
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª Down by the River Saile
â  ª And that was the end Of the woman in the woods
â  ª Weile weile waile
â  ª And that was the end of the baby too
â  ª Down by the River Saile
Subtitles : BTI Studios
ENGLISH ( SDH )